Japan, back to landing.
We're in the middle of the third of the
five meditations, and the first one was about
problems, the second one was
just taking care of yourself,
and you can try that if you like, but
it won't work. You
could either try it
or later,
it just doesn't work if you
only take care of what you want.
The beautiful things that will happen
when you truly care about yourself have
always been said that
you should take care of all living beings,
and you are a living being, so it's not a
choice between you and
others. That's not how it works. So if
everyone has the same right,
then you also have that right to happiness.
So the
suffering, self-sacrificing
Buddhist is not a good one. If you
hurt yourself to help others,
that's not a bad idea either,
because there will be a short break anyway.
So take care of everyone, including yourself.
I have many friends
who are good Buddhists and they do
n't take care of themselves, and um, they
work too much, and then they quit
or they get sick and have to
stop. So you have to take care of
yourself. You have to stay healthy because
otherwise you can't take care of
others.
We're going back to the text.
We'll gladly go through the Tibetan one, and you can,
you can do that.  Ignore it, but
maybe you can remember a few words.
This one line, I found it on
YouTube,
and then even a picture of him.
My brother is 72,
and he has a project in Montana.
They make firewood for
poorer people,
for those who only
have wood-burning stoves.
This picture represents
what happened to the singer because we severed
his limbs,
and
he offered to sacrifice half his
body.
He asked to have his
legs
in any fight that would benefit him,
but what was behind it was
his desire
to help others. Because of this,
his body was completely
restored.
We
stopped the country, or rather, it went crazy,
because we only went through this one line,
and we probably need 1000 years to finish it.
But
this story was simply beautiful, and
we translated it,
and if you want, you can read it too.
[Music] Back then,
because unlike Tokyo,
during the
[Music]
it was the time when Buddhism
spread rapidly,
and it still does, and
today it's just
the last [Music].  Physical therapy
instead of all over the world, and there are
also many Chinese who look at it. There are
certainly
7,000
temples. It's a classic
Buddhist city,
so if you have the opportunity to listen to
teachings there—it
's quite easy to get them there—
then I really recommend it. It's a
very, very beautiful, a very, very powerful
place. Um, we were just there
during the sakura, the cherry blossom season,
and
all the women, many women, walk around in
kimonos, and the class
just looks so graceful.
And
being in a city with
cherry blossoms is just as
important. In America, the Super Bowl
is just free,
and the people are just as euphoric. That's why
in America, the
Americans during the Super Bowl,
and
larger and also smaller
programs,
ACI and so on.
Yes, so
we've gone through
one line,
and
then there are examples in the text of
others who have
made similar sacrifices
simply to promote
how much fun it is to take care of
others and the needs of others.
And after that, we can begin with the exchange of ourselves
with others. He had it on his
head,
and
he cut it off
as an
offering.
And the next
story is
asking people.  I always remember how I
started, and that was in
1991 or so, and I was in New
York at the time, and
some people from the traditional school,
so not in session,
about 20 people, and they asked me
if I
could teach Tibetan because they
wanted to do
a three-year course and they were supposed to learn
the prayers,
so they didn't ask me if
I
could teach them theoretically,
and I thought, well,
maybe I'll teach them the
Sutra course,
because that's something all traditions have in
common. There's
a story
about a warrior woman,
the body of a
great, generous man, who
one day in the
forest met a tigress
who was very sick
and
had four cubs,
but she couldn't give him any milk,
and
how this is mentioned in the lamb race is
interesting because
he says, "
Cool Samira," and that means
because she was so desperate,
she almost ate
her own cubs,
so to
save the others, she would eat
one of her own cubs
so that she would have a little more strength to
feed the others,
and this prince
[music] decided to give
her his body,
and so
he  He
laid her down in front of the tigers and said, "
You can't stress her," and
then he... but she was too weak, and
he...
and then he used a stick to cut open his
chest so the tigress
could... um, as if
he were dying, he said to
her, "
If you
eat my flesh now, when I become a Buddha,
then you must be
my first disciple." And
then
we had the strength to do it, and she had her
cubs,
and those were later the
first disciples of the brother of the
disciples, and he taught them the
truths, and they saw and then, because of
this connection,
the truth,
and that was the first teaching he gave. He did
n't do it immediately after
his enlightenment; at
first, he thought no one would understand anyway.
[Music]
If so, more and more and you
teach yourself, then maybe you'll
also have this experience that
no one understands anyway,
or after enlightenment, for a few
weeks. I did
n't teach for seven weeks,
and then he probably
thought, "Oh well, maybe
someone will understand," and
then he did give teachings. But that
was the
story of
the tigress,
and
they also went through the
golden light, and
in that context...  I
taught this and I said back then
I really want to
teach, but I have a different
tradition of it.
So I would like to go that deep
in the classes, but you
have to ask your teacher if that's okay.
But
I would like to teach life lessons.
About half of them
stopped because Lama said
no, that's not possible, and
then I only had six or
seven students left, and that's how
NCI started. They started in
someone's kitchen back then. So if
you're interested,
it's a
great story.
The next line is about a famous
person,
a man
[music],
meaning
that our Lama
teaching, which lasted over 24
days, I do
n't know who did it. There were
probably
coffee breaks back then, but
[music]
the great compassion
became like this,
and these are all past lives. "
Flott" or "
long" means we ourselves
were chic, meaning only occupied. "Matrosch"
means nothing else.
Together, it means we are
focused on what we want.
That means people who are only
focused on getting what they
want would find it
difficult. If it's your habit to take
care of yourself first,
then
something like sacrificing your body would be difficult.
But what is
[Music]
If you want,
I wouldn't call it a sacrifice either,
but I would call it
sharing the body.
So, the king's sister gave
his body to another, but
that's not the point. Therefore, see
that you have cut through it.
He
offered his legs to the other person, but
he saw that other people
actually had the right to it,
and that also applies to your
money and your time and your
body.
And that
means the others also have a
right to your money, to your time.
For Germany, he sacrificed exactly half of
his body because he
understood
that the
same right
in the coming days,
and nobody lives there,
and the animals there are very
strange. And I had such a big
neon green moth, for example.
There was a silver mine,
that's my silver mine, and
probably wild animals were nearby.
And this line, this boundary,
I hear that's important, and
while you meditate this week,
it's not about you joyfully sharing
your body,
neck, and
[Music]
even today.
And that's because there's something called trying to make
bodies work,
and
he always told me about Mila herself.
We had a young man in the
class
[Music] who
had his  Packed his things
and
went into the woods.
This student, so the pupil,
You see, my teacher said
something like, he'll probably be back in the
week. My two [students] will be back in two
days and said, so do
n't try to make these actions even more
difficult. He
shared his body, I
sacrificed a few fingers, that's not how it works.
So take it slow. So
now it shouldn't be anything great,
just to draw people's
attention to it, but
quietly, those who are
best at it. You do
n't even get that
with a woman. It's a very good
example,
and he says, just pray
that you reach a point, oh, the
realization that others are the
same. It's enough to have your time and
your attention. Do
n't do all of this in one day,
but very slowly.
You also have to use the majority or the
understanding of the majority to
help everyone.
If you understand that,
then you can, or if you
achieve that, then you can help every life at the same time.
And do
n't try to achieve that beforehand. You
can manage it, but you work towards it,
and you have to see them directly.
People say, "I don't want to
learn clarity, I just want to
[music] with feeling." [Music]
A roebuck
outside
contributes to survival.
with their babies and just think about it
when you meditate, when you have something
good,
then at some point the point will come where
you no longer have any limitations,
like you
ten people. Take
this more sustainable approach, with this
understanding. With
a limited body, you ca
n't do that. Pray
more.
I translated it,
and it's simply not enough for Germany to
read it and say yes.
Just tell
the idea
that others have the same
right to happiness and also the same
right to your
time, maybe. And then think about it for a long time, because
then you'll do what you
should do. Why did you come into this world?
We have meditation
growing in the dark,
so
think about where you came from before
you
came into this world. During
this
period, you were in the dark, so in
the past, and the huge
darkness that lies before you in the future. In
between, there is only this short time in which
you can do something with your
life,
and at some point,
your time will run out, no matter
how much yoga you do. It will really be over,
so
do something worthwhile.
So the temptation to only satisfy your
needs wo
n't work anyway, so you
can serve better now if
later
Then between the two darknesses,
so you haven't been that long, so why not, why, why
shouldn't
you try to do everything right?
But here's another argument
[Music]
and this
great idea of ​​thinking overnight that
others would like instead of what
you would like.
Then it's
logical that I wanted to take care of something
else.
Why,
for example
[Music],
a grain field,
and today you have to drive an hour to
see a chalk field? But he said that
the people who have grain fields
here will also
[Music],
so you need
relatively fertile soil and things to grow. You
need a lot every year in the spring.
You have to prepare your garden,
so you can do it in ten
steps,
but it takes weeks in the garden
for the summer.
So think about this well-prepared
soil.
Then that
means that's the wish-
fulfilling
jewel.
8 days, yes, there's a wonderful
description of the wish-fulfilling
jewel. There's a ritual because you
wrap it in a silk
scarf, and one or
two full moons, you hang it on a
certain, hard surface,
so it hangs right there, and
then it's your wishes, like a
magic lamp, and that's
now this field
that  Are the other people? So this is
your ticket to happiness.
These are like a
field or a wish-fulfilling... There's
a great
joke about a magic lamp, but
this is just for
the guys here, and don't tell anyone. In
life, you want to have what
we want, but you have to
rub these wonders on this magic lamp. And I can say from my own
experience that I'm not that great at it,
but I try a little bit,
and it has made my life
truly wonderful.
Everything financially, friends,
my job—it
's all quite extraordinary. So
if you can just put a little bit of this
idea into practice,
then the results
of this way of thinking will be truly
extraordinary.
A life full of fun and happiness,
and lots of luck always seemed so
boring, but fun?
I'm in,
and it's fun.
[Music]
And he also says, in a non-
spiritual sense,
you get things
through others.
So other people have been going on
all day.
The fact that you can just sit here
comes from others.
So if you practically just take time for yourself,
practically just
for what you've already got,
the clothes you're wearing,
the green
[Music] [
Music]
arise.
It comes up in your book,
which means he  Yes, there is a
dependency,
other people already give you everything,
so don't forget too much, or
not, the attempt not to
be selfish,
and then it's pineapple, why,
because you had breakfast and
because you're wearing
underwear, at least I hope so, so
someone had to
grow the cotton, so
someone worked really hard so that
you have the things that are
now being shared in suffering, so
maybe forget for everyone, you should give someone
else simply by having
breakfast
[Music]
[Music],
for example, your mother,
and maybe I have to realize it when I get to 70, when
the decision for
a child is incredible
because
we're talking about 20 years of
investment
[Music]
in your life, all your time and
money
and the goodness of
her life
[Music],
then to produce milk,
you gladly do that as a
mother for up
to 20 years of your life on
your body,
so it
's not just
that people did
n't do that in past lives,
but
in past lives they had
[Music]
a baby
[Music],
you know, it was already your mother,
but it means butter,
I wanted to go
into a  I
came in with a Tibetan cup, I
wanted to be accepted into this
language, into this Tibetan class,
and then there were three lamas who were supposed to
decide whether I would be accepted
or not, whether I was good enough for it. The answer was
always yes,
and I said, oh dear, the weather here,
assuming I can
only have five people, and no, then he said,
just come, it's an
oral exam, and I sat down in front of
these very high-ranking lamas.
I sat down there, and these
three lamas...
I thought, oh God, this is going to be
terrible, and the other one said,
okay, I'll call on you now,
and I'm going to ask you about
Tibetan words,
and she said "Mama," yes, said "but,"
and he said "Papa."
So this word is very, very important
to me, but
now two... why
not
your mother?
And he said, "Here,
yes, you have an obligation
to love others because they were
your mother countless times,
but even if they weren't your
mother, you owe it in the forest to
attend to the needs of another.
Dress them, please, change
their diapers, pay for
them.
The reason we have children could be..."  It's
that we, he says, look,
everyone
was your mother countless times, but
today there
are eight billion people here,
and only one is your mother. But
the rest also take care of you all the time, look after you,
because you just have clothes on, and you ate
this morning.
Still taking care of you, looking after you.
We should think about it. It
owns everything you're wearing right now,
and everything is in your bag and in
your stomach.
To your mother and other people,
normal people, forget the
past. Food thing.
[Music]
Then he said,
but
it's great. Yes,
hello, you can buy it on Amazon.
I don't know any of the companies. I
trust him. It
means a small bag of
Tibetan monks
with small roasted flower seeds.
It's
unnecessary to have two forks to have breakfast.
If you're in church, there
's so much pressure there. You
have
so much time pressure, and you have to have
breakfast in your bag. You have
about three minutes, and then
you want these seeds with water, and it's very, very
quick,
but it tastes very, very good.
In a small bag,
if you have a very busy life,
it's very healthy. Yes, my wife
and I use it every day.
Always. You  This morning for breakfast you
had number one, which
means someone plants the plant. And
if you drive around in this part of Arizona,
you see how hard it is to be
a pharmacist.
I
helped out on the farms during my college days, helping the farmers. It's incredibly
hard work.
Someone
does it for you, even the
coffee machines. And it's really
total work,
and difficult work.
Someone went out and planted all these
things
in the village streets. You see people
jumping out in front of your car and
throwing things into the road, and you
drive over them. These are
the parts of the plant, and they try to break them open so they can get
the seeds out. It
's all very dangerous
work.
In the old days,
leading a cow across the green lawn was dangerous, and this kind of struggle would break them.
So someone does this.
Someone
has repaired the plants for you
so you can eat them.
For $25,
are you the one?
And the experience is worth telling.
Why does this come up at this point?
The work that people have done in your
food and
invested in your clothes is
incredible.
Someone is there in warm Galilee,
taking care of your clothes.
She has to do it, and it's
really hard work,
and people
live and die in these factories, and
they're hired for a
dollar.
The clothes on your body are the
result of great suffering. If you're
wearing clothes like everyone I see here,
and also
online participants
Satchy and I, we want a suit
design based on my taste,
and it has a
tie and
a suit jacket,
and we can work,
and someone has
...  All your clothes are made, and
that's very brutal.
These people already have a share
in your body because you have clothes
and you eat,
and they therefore earn a share of
your body because they
made it and they keep it warm.
So
they've already made an investment in
your body.
So I'll take one. Let's do
another paragraph.
If two people try, no matter
[music], whether
in a house or an
apartment or a temple,
the long form is
the kindness of other people.
That means the kindness that in
another person, by the way,
the book Katrin,
which is the prequel to How Yoga
Works, has been published in Ukraine.
Right now, the book Katrin
in
Ukraine, a
Ukrainian
Ukrainian case, has published it,
and it's available for
purchase in Ukraine. The one-piece costs
99 cents.
If you
speak Ukrainian, you can buy one. They need
many animals and many people,
and the foundation is needed so that this
house can be built.
Nobody chopped up the wood
from the trees
to transport the water and
build the house, not just the clothes
you wear,
what you ate this morning.
If you're
sitting in a place
where you can drive on a road...  You
could,
they are already a part of yourself,
the house you are currently living in, this
temple,
this temple was built with the hands of the
first generation, and I
remember
she was 57 at the time,
she
carried stones,
and many did nothing.
[Music]
You are in connection with the
first generation when you are in these
cabins,
the
three year-end cloths, each of them
paid for these houses and built them with their own hands,
and then whenever you meet them, you
should thank them, they
also had a house,
and they donated them,
they gave their money to
build these houses, and then they
donated them.
You are already in contact with
other people when you are in the house
because they built this house for them,
built it for you.
I also
built my father a house, and it is
really hard work, and someone else
helped build my house,
and it is hard, and you can
hurt yourself doing it. Then he says, "
What is this?" That is a
Buddhist person. That is his
robe
or his sleeping bag.
[Music]
A few times warm, long piece
that he can endure, and where he
cannot sleep under a tree.  In the old
Asian tradition, it
is
painful to
wear this cloak.
Every person and every nun has this
cloak; it is
very warm.
It is cheaper to make them from wool,
not cotton,
because there was
n't much cotton, but many
sheep
meant many sheep.
Someone took the sheep's fleece.
Someone had to have it. To wear
something,
something is finished so that you can wear it.
That means, in summary,
he is telling and reporting, so he is talking about
the T-shirt you are wearing,
the simplest piece of clothing you are
wearing, how many people
were involved in making it possible for you to wear it.
And that is always connected with a lot of
work: creating it,
making it, bringing it to the store,
washing it for you—that is connected with a lot of
work.
[Music]
So, at this point, we will also do
a little meditation, and I would like to
invite you to produce it again today.
We did the
Equal Rights Meditation,
a retrospective
meditation,
to look at what they wanted, what you wanted.
Can you connect that in a
better way
if you do it without conflict?
We do it so
that everyone has the same right,
and then, of course, the question arises: do the
other person have a  Always the
same right to your time, do
you have a right to their time, yes or
no?
You could spend your time wherever
you want. I can
drive and spend my time however I want.
Is that okay? That's a question, but
now it gets a little more difficult.
Now
we have a right to your time
because you ate this morning,
because you got dressed this morning,
and because you're sitting here in a
house. So
that's a motivation to work,
so the connection between other
people,
whether they perhaps have a right to your
time.
And good thought,
now we'll do a different meditation. They do that too,
somehow,
and we call it the Croissant Meditation.
It's about
taking something simple from your space, for
example, a piece of toast or a green
drink, a piece of music, or for example,
fruit. Fruit is really a lot of work to
make. Take something this
afternoon
that you ate,
or something. Let's
take something you ate,
and then go back.
Who brought that to your cabin? He bought it
at the store.
He brought it to the
store. He
ultimately delivered it to the store. Who
built the road that the truck
drove on? He brought it to the store.
He planted the tree,
he watered the tree where the fruit
grew.
It's really hard work.
A small piece of food—
that could be your meditation today,
your meditation
object. Go back,
and then
we'll go deeper. There's
another meditation, and
it's beautiful.
You do this backward
meditation first. First,
do a backward
meditation with a physical object,
like a piece of food you
ate today. And when you
do your motivation this evening, this afternoon,
you do a backward
meditation
with a piece of food or a piece of
clothing.
Much of this is pure imagination.
Someone, somewhere, brought it to this store,
then brought it to the booths.
Someone planted it.
And then I want you to go further back.
A person who planted this fruit
used seeds from a plant
that was planted there before, and
this plant is also based on seeds
from other plants that no longer
exist. And this is all a result
of 50,000 years of teamwork. A
few apples on... Is
someone from that generation? It's
really a lot of work,
but
someone planted the original plant that...  The
next plant has been
made.
50,000
human generations have
worked so that you can eat an apple. Since
earlier times,
generations of people have cared for the seeds
of the fruits and the fields so that
the fruit is brought to you today.
Employees in my cafe,
and it's a lot of paperwork,
and that's 50,000 years of
paperwork
going back.
Let's do this. How much time do we have left?
10 minutes.
[Music]
This meditation,
okay, we'll start. And
okay, I'd like to offer you the
lemonaries. These are
preparatory exercises.
So choose a piece of food
and fresh juice.
Choose some
juice or a piece of red or white,
whatever comes up.
[Music]
Who brought this to your home
or here to this temple? Thank them.
Try to change your mind about how they
look.
And then try to imagine where
they bought it, maybe from
a shop. And imagine those
people working there,
putting the food on the displays. They
work all day. It's hard work.
Someone made the money.
Someone made the paper of money.
Nobody made the plastic of the
credit card. Someone made that
Online banking is being developed;
hundreds of people are
involved.
Someone bought the vegetables and fruit from
the garden.
I did that in college. I
loaded the food into the truck, carried it into the
truck, and it's really
hard work.
Someone
selected this fruit and these vegetables, packed them into crates; it's
really hard work.
Someone watered the fields,
fertilized and harvested them, and
also cleared the fields of
weeds.
They are already
a part of our bodies, time,
so they have a right to a part of
our time.
They have a right to what
we do with our bodies, a part of it.
They have a right to thank them,
and the thought of thanking them,
and that is the thought
that they have a right to a
part of our work,
also has a story,
and that is the second meditation
I want to do for you today.
The idea of
thinking about it,
the idea that other people have the
same right to a part of my time.
I find this idea...
What is the line for this idea?
I heard it
in the country,
and then I want you to mentally go
back the thought trains that introduce you
to this point
today: the possibility
that other
people already have a share, a right, to
your time.
If we respect the idea that
everyone in this space of this world
has fundamental rights,
then
people fundamentally have a right
to your time because they
fed me, they gave you their time,
they gave you your clothes,
and they made your house.
Where did this
idea of
equality first come from? Why am
I talking about this? Because I heard about
this man.
I had a thought; I thought
I'd like to hear more about it.
What did you envision?
I considered what improvements
I could make. I heard about this honor, about
Lamarim.
Where does this come from? I think
when I was in college, I heard
about Buddhism. I did
n't study it, but I heard about it,
and I thought about what had happened before
I
went to college.
This comes from my family.
When I think about what
my mother and father
said about going
to college, during
my high school years,
I thought about history and the
rest of the world.
And in elementary school,
I remember when I
went to my first class,
and I remember how I felt.  I
have
and how
interested but also respectful I was when I
went over these books, and I
remember
the first few days before I was allowed to go
to school for the first time.
I was with my mother, with
my father, with my family. I
remember things we
talked about,
thoughts I had. I
remember a day in my
nursery when I
touched a toy and how soft it
was, and I thought about the softness
and what I want you to do.
Do two different kinds of meditation. One is with a
physical object. Take something you
ate, something you were afraid of, something you drank,
a house
you are currently working in, and go right to
all the people. Yes, and that was sacred. To make
these materials,
all the people who contributed their knowledge
to build houses, and
thank them. Go back and thank them.
Gratitude is a truly healthy
and happy activity that creates happiness.
And in the second meditation
you should do today, there are those of
you who have also taken a step. There is a
prime time, a priority time, and one
that is mid-morning,
and there you look back in your
thoughts and see how far back.  You
can go
[music]
and you can go back
to the days when you were a baby and when
you were just born.
It's possible to go back
and maybe you can break through.
Maybe you can
go to the spaces where you were
before this birth. It's
possible
that your thoughts flow in a stream
all the time you are aware of. You have a
recording in your mind of past
lives. You just have to try to access them. So
why do we work on going back
with your food, your
clothes, your house, and
being grateful?
If that's why,
with an even deeper meditation,
your mind is fresh, you go back into
your thoughts step by step by step.
And that is a very, very deep
meditation, and it has a great influence
on
seeing in the long term.
That is the exercise of letting your thoughts flow back,
and by getting better,
it's true. On the first day, it will
be a little difficult, but after a
week,
you will be much, much better at it,
and that has a lot of power to
have the ability
to see most things directly.
So, two different types of
retrospective meditation: one of
a fruit or a car or a
house, and the other
is a meditation
where you trace your thoughts back and
you see which thought came.  Before the
last thought
[Music]
You can trace every thought back,
you can remember, oh, I had
this thought ten years ago
and twelve years ago, and if you
practice this,
you can
see where you were before this life, and
it's a lot of fun, and most importantly,
you remember all those
thoughts you've already had there. Okay, guys,
take a drink, lie down,
stretch, have a drink.
Okay, see you tomorrow
at 3 PM Berlin time,
and it's fun being with you.
Thank you so much, I see your
smiling, beautiful faces.
Thank you to Franziska and all the
staff.
Thank you
to the translators, and see you
tomorrow at 6 AM Arizona time and at 3
PM Berlin time.